Guide to the Ted Fagan Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
- Reel to reel tapes
  - Royaumont Festival. Tourel, Jennie, soprano and Puyana, Rafael, 1931-, harpsichord. Part II1962, 7" reel (Box 19, Folder 487)
  - Gottlieb, Jack. Twilight crane. Fantasy for Woodwind Quintet March 24, 1962, 5" reel (Box 19, Folder 488)
    First Performance. Commissioned by the New York Philharmonic Woodwind Quintet. Gomberg, Harold, conductor. NBC TV Recital Hall
  - Rehearsal with Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, 5" reel (Box 19, Folder 489)
  - (Box 19, Folder 490)
  - Hungarian Folklore Music. Collected by Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945. (From his collection), 7" reel (Box 19, Folder 491)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Variations sur le thême God save the King, 7" reel (Box 19, Folder 492)
  - Rehearsal with Tourel, Jennie, soprano. 1963, 7" reel (Box 19, Folder 493)
    Gottlieb, Jack. Cavafy
  - Farrow, Edward R. That Affair. London., 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 494)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 2, op. 18, C minor, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 495)
    Janis, Byron, piano
  - Wiener Festwochen. Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Symphony, no. 9. 1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 496)
    Bayrischer Rundfunkorchester. Kubelík, Rafael, 1914-1996, conductor
  - Wiener Festwochen. Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Symphony, no. 9. 1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 497)
  - Wiener Festwochen. Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Symphony, no. 9. 1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 498)
  - Wiener Festwochen. London, George, 1920-1985, bass-baritone Recital. Part I1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 499)
    with Werbe, Erik, piano. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Atlas; Ihr Bild; Fischermädchen; Stadt; Am Meer; Doppelgänger -- Ibert, Jacques, 1890-1962. Don Quichotte. Chanson du départ; Chanson à Dulcinée; Chanson du duc; Chanson de la mort -- Mussorgsky, Modest Petrovich, 1839-1881. Songs and dances of death
  - Wiener Festwochen. London, George, 1920-1985, bass-baritone Recital. Part II1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 500)
  - Peters, Roberta, 1930-, soprano, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 501)
    Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Lucia di Lammermoor. Regnava nel silenzio -- Quando rapito in estasi -- Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Puritani. Son vergin vezzosa; Qui la voce sua soave; Vien diletto -- Sonnambula. Ah! non credea mirarti; Ah! non giunge
  - Thai Folk-Music, 5" reel (Box 20, Folder 502)
  - UN General Assembly Meeting (Tape missing)Nov. 22, 1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 503)
  - Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957. The Parma years., 5" reel (Box 20, Folder 504)
    Gillis, Don, 1912-1978
  - Instrumental, 5" reel (Box 20, Folder 505)
    Koch, Lothar, oboe. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concerto, oboe, K. 285 (314) C major. Berliner Philharmoniker. Karajan, Herbert von, conductor -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Italienische Serenade. Zagrebacki solisti
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Jesu, der du meine Seele (Cantata), 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 506)
  - Unreleased Test Pressings of Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962 and Nilsson, Birgit, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 507)
    R.C.A. Victor Test Pressing Bs 101164. April 1, 1936. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Backer-Grøndahl, Agathe, 1847-1907. Barnets vardag. Mot kvæld -- Columbia Test Pressing XAX - 1216 - 1N. July 17, 1957. Nilsson, Birgit. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Fliegende Holländer. Jo-ho-hoe! Traft ihr das Schiff; Tannhäuser. Dich, teure Halle; Lohengrin. Einsam in trüben Tagen; Tristan und Isolde. Liebestod -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera. Ma dall' arido stelo divulsa; Forza del destino. Pace, pace, mio Dio; Aïda. Ritorna vincitor; O patria mia
  - Souzay, Gérard, 1918-2004, baritone1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 508)
    Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Bonne chanson
  - Original Soundtrack to Shall we dance?1937, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 509)
    Astaire, Fred and Rogers, Ginger, singers. Gershwin, George, 1898-1937 and Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983. I've got beginner's luck; They all laughed; Dance; Let's call the whole thing off; They can't take that away from me; Ballet; Shall we dance?; Finale: they all laughed
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Grande Messe des morts, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 510)
    Part II
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Falstaff. Part I Mar. 21, 1964, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 511)
    Colzani, Anselmo as Sir John Falstaff; Tucci, Gabriella as Alice Ford; Sereni, Mario as Ford; Resnik, Regina, 1922- as Dame Quickly; Alva, Luigi as Fenton; Raskin, Judith as Nannetta; Elias, Rosalind as Meg Page. Metropolitan Opera Orchestra. Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990, conductor (Second part in tape No.849)
  - Original Soundtrack of Pennies from Heaven. 1936, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 512)
    Singers: Crosby, Bing 1903-1977; Fellows, Edith, 1923-; Meek, Donald E.; Armstrong, Luis. Songs: Burke, Johnny, 1908-1964 and Johnston, Arthur. So do I; Old Mac Donald had a farm; Pennies from heaven; Skeleton in the closet; Let's call a heart a heart; Pennies from heaven. One, two, button my shoe; So do I, reprise; Finale
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Grande Messe des morts, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 513)
    Parts I and 3
  - Chamlee, Mario, 1892-1966, tenor, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 514)
    (Taped from discs) Opera selections
  - Schwarzkopf, Elisabeth, soprano sings, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 515)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Alte; Kleine Spinnerin; Kinderspiel; Zauberer; Zufriedenheit, K. 473; Sehnsucht nach dem Frühlinge
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Manfred, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 516)
    No index card
  - Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950. Jasager, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 517)
  - Crespin, Régine, soprano. Selections from a London Festival Hall concert1963, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 518)
    Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Damnation de Faust. Autrefois un roi de Thulé; Amour est un flambeau
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816. Barbiere di Siviglia. Act II, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 519)
  - Tenors, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 520)
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 521)
  - Björling, Jussi, 1911-1960, tenor, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 522)
    Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Forelle (Song); Allmacht (Song); Ständchen, D. 889; Schöne Müllerin Wandern; Böse Farbe -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Es muss ein Wunderbares sein -- Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Eichendorff-Lieder. Verschwiegene Liebe
  - Tenors, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 523)
  - Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Mass of LIfe. Part I, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 524)
  - Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Mass of LIfe. Part II, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 525)
    Holst, Gustav, 1874-1934. Hymn of Jesus
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Snegurochka. Part I, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 526)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Snegurochka. Part II, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 527)
  - Cumming, Richard. We happy few. NBC-TV Broadcast Nov. 29, 1964, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 528)
    Performers: Gramm, Donald, bass-baritone; Cumming, Richard, piano
  - Rehearsal with Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 529)
  - Marlowe, Christopher, 1564-1593. Dr. Faustus. Part I. WBAI recording, 7" reel (Box 20, Folder 530)
    Actors: Hatfield, Hurd; Croft, Wayne; Hammond, Tom; Robinson, Paul; Ashe-Croft, Terry; MacIntyre, Wayne; Tenley, Theodore; Gilliam, D. F.; Richardson, Wells; Varon, Rena
  - Marlowe, Christopher, 1564-1593. Dr. Faustus. Part I. WBAI recording, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 531)
  - Pope Paul VI at the United NationsOct. 4, 1965, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 532)
  - Pergolesi and Honegger, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 533)
    Pergolesi, Giovanni Battista, 1710-1736. Serva padrona -- Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955. Judith (Opera)
  - Reyer, Ernest, 1823-1909. Sigurd, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 534)
    Reyer, Ernest, 1823-1909. Sigurd. Singers: Botiaux, Gustave; Cumia, Lyne; Silvy, Jacqueline; Bianco, René; Giband, Felix -- Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816. Barbiere di Siviglia. Rizzieri, Elena, singer; Oncina, Juan, 1925-, tenor; Capecchi, Fernando; Bruscantini, Sesto, bass-baritone. Fasano, Renato, 1902-1979, conductor
  - Vocal and instrumental music by Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 535)
    (Taped from commercial discs)
  - Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; Weill, Kurt, 1900-1950; Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 536)
  - Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Hugh the drover 1924, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 537)
    Lewis, Mary as Mary; Walker, ? as Susan; Willis, Constance as Jane; Davies, Tudor, 1892-1958, as Hugh; Collier, Frederick as John; Falkner, Keith, 1900- as Constable. Sargent, Malcolm, Sir, 1895-1967, conductor. H. M. Theater, London.
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Parsifal -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Daphne, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 538)
    Parsifal. Act III. Pistor, Gotthelf as Parsifal; Hoffmann, Ludwig as Gurnemanz; Bronsgeest, Cornelis as Amfortas. Staatskapelle Berlin. Muck, Karl, conductor. Recorded in Berlin 1928 or 29 -- Daphne. Bampton, Rose as Daphne; Dermota, Anton as Leukippos; Svanholm, Set as Apollo; Weber, Ludwig as Peneios; Kindermann, Lydia, 1891-1954 as Gaea. Kleiber, Erich, 1890-1956, conductor. As performed on Sept. 17, 1948 in the Teatro Colón, Buenos Aires, Argentina.
  - Caplet, André, 1878-1925. Miroir de Jésus, mystères du RosaireApr. 21, 1943, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 539)
    Tourel, Jennie, mezzo-soprano. CBS broadcast.
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990. Kaddish. Part I and II Dec. 1963, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 540)
    Tel Aviv performance
  - Opera Miscellaneous, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 541)
  - Radio Programs from the forties. WEAF; WOR; WABC; WNEW Stations, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 542)
    Popular songs 1945- 47
  - Radio Programs from the forties. WEAF; WOR; WABC; WNEW Stations, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 543)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Part I Dec. 12, 1969, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 544)
    Metropolitan Opera House performance.
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Part II Dec. 12, 1969, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 545)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon. Part III Dec. 12, 1969, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 546)
  - Blomdahl, Karl Birger, 1916-1968. Aniara June 15, 1959, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 547)
  - Fields, Gracie, 1898-1979 Transfers I1963, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 548)
    KISMET. Singers: Merrill, Robert; Resnik, Regina, 1922-; Leigh, Adele, 1928-2004; McKenna, Kenneth J., 1931-; Wallace, Ian; S. Mike (illeg.). That certain smile -- Wish you were here -- Three coins in a fountain -- As time goes by -- There's a place for me -- Each time I fall in love -- Chi sará, sará -- Small world -- Hey there -- Accustomed to his face -- All at once, you love him -- Love is a many-splendored thing -- Loveliest night of the year -- Sing as we go -- Young at heart -- You didn't want me -- Mrs. Binn's twins -- Kerry dance
  - Fields, Gracie, 1898-1979 Transfers II, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 549)
    Mother's wedding group -- Vie en rose -- September song -- Ugly duckling -- Lord's prayer -- Underneath the arches -- How deep is the ocean -- Play to me Gipsy -- Isle of Capri -- One night of love -- One night of love (diff. version) -- Home -- Keeping up with the Jones' -- I belong to Glasgow -- Enery. He forgot to come home -- You're more than all the world to me -- Song of the bells -- Mary Rose -- Sing as we go -- House is haunted -- Love, wonderful love -- Love is everywhere -- Altogether and smiling -- Gracie Fields' Medley -- Love's last word -- Now it can be told -- Donkey serenade (1935) -- One day when we were young -- Danny boy -- Gracie and the troops in France -- Gracie and the navy -- Dream lover -- Ave Maria -- A little love a little kiss -- Holy City -- Land of hope and glory -- Christopher Robin is saying his prayers -- Wish me luck -- Gracie thanks (1939)
  - Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921, tenor, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 550)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers I, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 551)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers II, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 552)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers III, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 553)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers IV, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 554)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers V, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 555)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers VI, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 556)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers VII, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 557)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers VIII, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 558)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers IX, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 559)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers X, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 560)
  - Miscellaneous opera singers XI, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 561)
  - Robin, Mado, soprano, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 562)
    Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Mireille. Selections. Orchestre du Conservatoire du centre de Paris. Blareau, Richard, conductor -- Rico, J. Fascination, taped from disc, Souvenirs de la belle époque -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata. Parigi, o cara, noi lasceremo
  - Vocal transfers, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 563)
  - Vocal transfers, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 564)
  - Vocal transfers, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 565)
  - Vocal transfers, 7" reel (Box 21, Folder 566)
  - Vocal transfers, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 567)
  - Melba, Nellie, Dame, 1861-1931, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 568)
  - On a note of triumph, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 569)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei, 1873-1943. Concertos, piano, orchestra, no. 3, op. 30, D minor, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 570)
    Weissenberg, Alexis, piano. New York Philharmonic Orchestra. Wallenstein, Alfred, conductor
  - Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Ritorno d'Ulisse in patria, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 571)
  - Vocal Transfers. Duets, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 572)
  - Mardones, José, 1868-1932, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 573)
  - Tenors, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 574)
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 575)
  - Basses and Baritones, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 576)
  - Mezzos and Contraltos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 577)
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 578)
  - Ensembles, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 579)
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 580)
  - Vocal Transfers. Duets, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 581)
  - Lehmann, Lilli, 1848-1929, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 582)
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 583)
  - Fields, Gracie, 1898-1979, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 584)
    Gracie and the navy(continued from tape 549) -- Somewhere over the rainbow -- Grandest song of all -- Wood-pecker's song -- If I should fall in love again -- When my dreams grow old -- Little drummer boy -- Indian love call - Rose Marie
  - Douglas, Norman reads Limericks. Private, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 586)
    Marlow, Sylvia, harpsichord
  - Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973 reads his poetry at the United Nations. Part IApril 11, 1972, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 587)
    (Original)
  - Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973 reads his poetry at the United Nations. Part IIApril 11, 1972, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 588)
  - Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973 reads his poetry at the United Nations. Part IApril 11, 1972, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 589)
    (English. Fagan, Ted, interpreter)
  - Neruda, Pablo, 1904-1973 reads his poetry at the United Nations. Part IIApril 11, 1972, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 590)
  - Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921, tenor. Transfers, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 591)
  - Hidalgo, Ginamaría. Recuerdos de una viaja canción. Part I, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 592)
  - Hidalgo, Ginamaría. Recuerdos de una viaja canción. Part II, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 593)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Memorial I, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 594)
    (Second copy)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Memorial II, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 595)
  - Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963 Memorial III, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 596)
  - 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 597)
    (Tape and card missing)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Missa brevis, K. 115, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 598)
  - Mezzos and Contraltos, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 599)
  - Edison Originals Vol. 11 unissued, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 600)
    "These were dug up by the Voicewriters people for re-issue promotionally in 1956 but they were never re-pressed. This dub is from a trial acetate." Destinnová, Ema, 1878-1930, soprano. Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Madama Butterfly. Un bel dì, vedremo. (Recorded Dec. 1911. No.82527) -- Kaschmann, Giuseppe, 1847-1925, baritone. Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Hamlet. O vin, dissipe la tristesse. (Recorded 1910, unpublished) -- Bori, Lucrezia, 1887-1960, soprano. Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801. Matrimonio segreto. Selection. (Recorded 1911, unpublished) -- De Cisneros, Elenora, singer. Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864. Prophète. Ah! mon fils (Recorded 1910, unpublished) -- Slezak, Leo, 1873-1946, tenor; Rappold, Marie, 1873-1957, soprano. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello. Già nella notte densa. (Recorded Apr. 1911, unpublished) -- Korsoff, Lucette, 1876-1955, soprano. Auber, D. F. E. (Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871. Manon Lescaut. C'est l'histoire amoureuse (1910)
  - Various vocal transfers from William R. Moran, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 601)
    Sten, Suzanne, alto. Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Hérodiade. Il est doux, il est bon; Cid. Pleurez, pleurez, mes yeux -- Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Lieder nach Rückert. Ich atmet' einen linden Duft; Lieder und Gesänge aus der Jugendzeit. Hans und Grethe -- Dadmun, Royal, singer. Indian love lyrics. Less than the dust; When I am dying -- Butt, Clara, Dame, 1872-1936, contralto. Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Serse. Ombra mai fù -- Ginster, Ria, singer. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Unendlichen -- McCormack, John, 1884-1945, tenor; Tibbett, Lawrence, 1896-1960, baritone; Thibault, Conrad, baritone. Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Semele. Selections; McCormack, John, 1884-1945, tenor; Floridante. Caro amore; Theodora. Defend her, Heav'n! -- Cortez, Viorica mezzo-soprano. Gomes, Carlos, 1836-1896. Maria Tudor. Scena and aria, Act IV.
  - Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Daphne Sept. 17, 1948, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 602)
    Recorded from a special LP released by the Musicians Foundation, 131 Riverside Dr. NYC 1964. Courtesy of William R. Moran. Bampton, Rose as Daphne; Svanholm, Set as Apollo; Dermota, Anton as Leukippos; Weber, Ludwig as Peneios; Kindermann, Lydia, 1891-1954 as Gaea; Shepherds: Matiello, Angel; di Toto, Humberto; Gagliardo, Tulio; Barbieri, Hector; servants: Rinaldi, Mafalda; Palmieri, Norma. Orquesta y Coro del Teatro Colon, Buenos Aires. Kleiber, Erich, 1890-1956, conductor
  - Various vocal transfers from William R. Moran, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 603)
    Van Diemen, Ursula, singer. Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Vesperae de Dominica. Laudate Dominum -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Ave Maria (from the unfinished opera, Loreley) -- Souez, Ina, soprano. Chocolate soldier -- My hero -- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ernani. Ernani, Ernani, involami -- Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835. Norma. Casta diva
  - Reina, Jorge interviews Ocampo, Victoria, 1890-1979 on Women's Year and Women's Rights. Part I, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 604)
    Ocampo, founder (1931) and publisher of the Argentine magazine Sur, the most important literary magazine of its time in Latin America.
  - Reina, Jorge interviews Ocampo, Victoria, 1890-1979 on Women's Year and Women's Rights. Part II, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 605)
  - Bathori, Jane, 1877-1970, mezzo-soprano, 7" reel (Box 22, Folder 606)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Masses, K. 317, C major, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 607)
    Donath, Helen, soprano; Davies, Ryland, 1943-, tenor. London Symphony Orchestra. Davis, Colin, 1927-, conductor
  - Tenors, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 608)
    Ghari, Julio, tenor. Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aida. Celeste Aida -- Wunderlich, Fritz, 1930-1966, tenor. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Einsame; Frühlingsglaube; An Sylvia; Heidenröslein; Ständchen; Liebhaber in allen Gestalten -- Lortzing, Albert, 1801-1851. Waffenschmied. Selection
  - Instrumentals, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 609)
    Bradshaw, David, piano. Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Mazurka, piano, op. 33, no. 2, D major. Transcribed to C major; Waltzes, piano, C# minor. arr. -- Jazz Masques -- Reverberi, Gian Piero. Elaborations, op.10, no.3, E major -- Campoli, Alfredo, 1906-1991, violin; Tryon, Valerie, piano. Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886. Transcription of Chopin's Mazurka, op.6, no.2, C# minor for violin and piano
  - Missa Flamenca and Missa Mozarabe, 5" reel (Box 23, Folder 610)
  - Piano Music, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 611)
  - United General Assembly. Session adjourned, 5" reel (Box 23, Folder 612)
    Chilean representative's speech is interrupted by Roa, Raúl, Cuban minister of foreign affairs (1959-73). (English version, see tape 1034)
  - Various British Prime Ministers, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 613)
    MacDonald, James Ramsay, 1866-1937. Broadcast Nov. 5, 1935 -- Chamberlain, Neville, 1869-1940. Broadcast Sept. 3, 1939, declaration of war; Broadcast May 10, 1940, resignation -- Attlee, C. R. (Clement Richard), 1883-1967. Broadcast Jluy 30, 1950 -- Eden, Anthony, Earl of Avon, 1897-1977. Broadcast July 17, 1956. Young Conservatives and Unionists Rally -- Macmillan, Harold, 1894-1986. 1st Earl of Stockton. At the UN, Sept. 29, 1960; Kent Conservative Rally, Canterbury July 27, 1963 -- Douglas. Home. Lord Mayor's Banquet. Nov. 11, 1963
  - Great American Speeches, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 614)
    American jurist in the Supreme Court from 1902 to 1932. Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935. On his 90th birthday. March 7, 1931 -- Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945. First inaugural address. March 4, 1933 -- Rogers, Will, 1879-1935. Morgenthau's Plan. April, 28, 1935 -- Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964. War comes to Europe. Sept. 1, 1939 -- Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945. Declaration of War. Dec. 8, 1941 -- Lawyer and Republican nominee for the 1940 presidential election. Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944. Loyal Opposition. Nov. 11, 1940 -- Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969. Order of the Day. June 6, 1944 -- Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972. The Truman Doctrine. March 12, 1947 -- Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959. The Marshall Plan. June 5, 1947
  - Spoleto festival of two worlds. Latin American poets read their own poems1970/71, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 615)
    Pacheco, José Emilio (Mexico). Brusco olor de azufre; Descripción de un naufragio en ultramar (1939) -- Paz, Octavio, 1914-1998 (Mexico). Madrugada; Aquí; Madurai; Presente; Viento entero -- Godoy, Tamara. (Chile) Del libro Copaiá Pu. A guisa de prólogo; Copaiá; Corazón, viejo indio; Eres de un material (a quien nadie puso nombre) -- Nadie es tanto tu (cuando me amas) -- A la muerte de Nacimiced. Monumento Mortuorio.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945. Excerpts of speeches -- "The Kennedy Wit.", 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 616)
    Young democratic clubs. Aug. 25, 1935 -- Second acceptance speech: Rendez-vous with destiny. June 27, 1936 -- Harvard University Tercentenary. Spet. 18, 1936 -- Fiftieth Anniversary of the Statue of Liberty. Oct. 28, 1936 -- Address at Madison Square Garden, New York. Oct. 31, 1936 -- Second inaugural address. "One third of a nation." Jan. 20, 1937 -- Address at Bonneville dam. Sept. 28, 1937 -- "Quarantine" speech. Chicago Illinois. Oct. 5, 1937 -- Fireside chat on economic conditions. Apr. 14, 1938 -- National Education Association. June 30, 1938 --Annual message to congress. Jan. 4, 1939 -- Fireside chat on war in Europe. Sept. 3, 1939 -- Jackson Day dinner. Jan. 8, 1940 -- University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Virginia. June 10, 1940 -- Philadelphia Campaign Speech. Oct. 23, 1940 -- Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963. "The Kennedy Wit." Introduced by Brinkley, David and Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965. 1960 Campaign; Press Conference; Presidency; Family
  - Sopranos, 7" reel (Box 23, Folder 617)